[
    {
        "﻿question": "What is the general introduction to the case of China Mobile Zhejiang?",
        "answer": "In 2022, China Mobile Zhejiang's operating revenue reached 67 billion RMB, or about 10 billion dollars.\nIn To C, there are 77.5 million mobile users, accounting for about 60% of the total revenue. The mobile penetration rate is far higher than 100%. About 120,000 5G base stations have been built.\nThe total revenue of home broadband is about 15%. Currently, there are more than 20 million broadband users, with a market share of about 60%, among which gigabit users account for 25%.\nChina Mobile Zhejiang now serves more than 7000 To B enterprises, accounting for more than 20% of the total revenue. It is planned that the proportion of TO B revenue will reach 40% by 2025. TO B will become a new second growth curve, a new growth engine.\nHuawei and China Mobile Zhejiang have been cooperating with each other since 2014 in terms of infrastructure, O&M, and digital services, helping China Mobile Zhejiang achieve business success."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is the digital transformation strategy of China Mobile Zhejiang?",
        "answer": "China Mobile Zhejiang continues to actively implement the Group's strategic deployment, anchors the development orientation of the \"world-class information service technology innovation company\", and continuously explores and practices the road of digital transformation with the main line of \"promoting digital transformation and achieving high-quality development\".\n1. In the digital infrastructure field, we have built the foundation for cloud-and-network synergy, intelligent and efficient intelligent connections by relying on core digital technology capabilities.\n2.  In the O&M digital field, we have reconstructed the operation mode and improved user experience with the support of AI. Provide users with assured and high-quality information and communication services.\n3. In the digital business field, we enrich 5G digital life applications, promote 5G integration into the core social and economic sectors, and continuously consolidate the new foundation of the digital economy."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does China Mobile Zhejiang promote the transformation of digital intelligence?",
        "answer": "As we know, the digital intelligence transformation is a systematic project. China Mobile Zhejiang promotes the transformation through the following four key steps:\n1. Perception system establishment: A three-dimensional integrated perception evaluation system is systematically established to bridge networks and business scenarios from network performance, service quality, and customer experience, implementing intelligent perception, automatic analysis, and closed-loop decision-making.\n2. Converged platform evolution: Continuously build solid data foundation (O+B+S converged data governance) and intelligent engine (policy+AI+knowledge computing) to support various application scenarios.\n3. Optimization of the production process: Proactively identified process breakpoints, greatly improved the production efficiency and customer experience through the intelligent data platform and capabilities, and supported major processes such as complaint handling, satisfaction management, and poor-quality work order management.\n4. Joint technological innovation: Since 2014, with the evolution of network technologies and the continuous enrichment of service scenarios, China Mobile Zhejiang, together with partners such as Huawei, has continuously intensified technological innovation and incubated multiple innovative UCs and capabilities in the To C, To H, and To B fields. Includes VOLTE, VONR, CCM, LOT, 5G To B, and Product Broadband Assistant."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does China Mobile Zhejiang improve user experience &  customer satisfaction & Experience-driven digital intelligence transformation?",
        "answer": "In fact, China Mobile Zhejiang started its experience transformation journey in 2014. After nearly 10 years of practice and innovation, it has formed a leading knowledge and experience system.\n1. To C: Change from passive to proactive to improve customer satisfaction. China Mobile Zhejiang has 77 million To C subscribers, with a market share of 70%. How to turn the \"invisible and untouchable\" customer experience into \"evaluable and analytical\" certainty is a challenge. Based on AI modeling and knowledge calculation, identify derogatory users, and implement proactive satisfaction management and improvement through end-to-end fault demarcation, location, rectification, and effect evaluation. The number of derogatory users in the province dropped by 30%.\n2. To H: from connections to services, leading high-quality home broadband. China Mobile Zhejiang's HBB market share is 60.9%. How to improve the HBB satisfaction and reduce the investment ratio per 10,000 is a must-answer question. The ADO solution (by deploying the AEC probe on the OLT) proactively detects and identifies the Internet access jam, disconnection, and slow problems, quickly analyzes and locates the problems, and quickly and efficiently resolves the problems in each service line, improving the customer satisfaction. Currently, China Mobile Zhejiang's HBB Group ranks among the top three in terms of customer satisfaction. It has achieved the broadband strategy of leading scale and quality. According to the best practice of China Mobile Huzhou, the ratio of home broadband investment per 10,000 is reduced by 52%.\n3. To B: From private lines to private networks, build deterministic SLAs. China Mobile Zhejiang's To B revenue accounted for 21% in 2012. There are about 7000 5G To B enterprises, with a new market share of 65%. The development potential is huge. China Mobile Zhejiang focuses on how to make To B service quality visible and manageable and ensure differentiated experience. A 5G To B experience assurance management system is built to make enterprise users visible and service quality manageable. Poor-quality demarcation takes less than 5 minutes."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does China Mobile Zhejiang promote O&M transformation?",
        "answer": "China Mobile Zhejiang and Huawei jointly build a new-generation fault management system, reconstructing the O&M mode with intelligent data and implementing value-driven O&M transformation.\n1. One fault, one work order, improving O&M efficiency. O&M personnel orchestrate alarm compression rules and combine the AI fault propagation diagram to compress 3.2 million alarms per day to 5400 work orders, implementing one work order for one fault and improving the overall troubleshooting efficiency by 30%.\n2. Event system innovation and O&M quality improvement. With the fault automation solution, network faults can be detected within 1 minute, located within 5 minutes, and rectified within 15 minutes, implementing automatic driving for minor faults and assisting decision-making for major faults.\n3. Everything is visible and O&M is visible. In routine monitoring and O&M, the headquarters can view, manage, and control the information on the entire network. By using the concept of digital twin network, the headquarters integrates multi-dimensional visualized information and transforms the traditional monitoring mode that relies on text information such as alarms and performance information into a graph-centered monitoring mode. Visualized command and dispatch mode with everything visible."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the To B practices of China Mobile Zhejiang?",
        "answer": "In the To B field, China Mobile Zhejiang has launched 5G To B services in the mall, covering 15 industries, including manufacturing, ports, and mining, and covering more than 40 standard products. And has built 28 provincial future factories and more than 170 5G demonstration factories in the province."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does the To H service of China Mobile Zhejiang develop?",
        "answer": "In the To H field, China Mobile Zhejiang adheres to the concept of \"grasping broadband means grasping the general trend\", continuously expands the family moat, from the network to the home and then to the new business field, and extends the \"Four Ones\" layer by layer to the pan-home market. Continue to expand its leading advantages in scale, market share, and quality, and achieve efficient matching of end-network service.\n1.  Emphasize both quantity and quality and strengthen the gigabit leadership. On the one hand, follow the principle of \"networks, terminals, and services follow the industry\" to ensure the overall gigabit user experience. On the other hand, through broadband/product/operation upgrade, optimize the gigabit user structure and achieve high-quality development.\n2.  As a differentiated weapon of gigabit broadband, FTTR is the contact point between carriers and every high-value user. FTTR is a strategic upgrade from \"simple networking products\" to \"building new marketing and production relationships for To H\".\n3.  To H product layout is gradually optimized for home users. Broadband TV is the basis (market share: 63.8%), surveillance and scenario-based services are the core (first in the group), and the innovation battleground is the whole house intelligence is the future, and the product pipeline has taken shape.\n4. Finally, extend the scenario to communities, villages, and shops. Focus on monitoring and business broadband, build a one-kilometer life circle for all families, and strive to compete for the market landscape."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the Quality Connection/ToC/BEST network practices of China Mobile Zhejiang?",
        "answer": "As a pioneer in China's 5G construction, China Mobile Zhejiang has maintained a leading network since building the first 5G city in 2018 and will further build the first 5G-A city this year.\nLast year, China Mobile Zhejiang ranked first in 10 excellent scenarios and ranked first in 5G speed crowdtesting, bringing excellent 5G experience to users. The leading network and experience helped China Mobile Zhejiang seize the market opportunity and won the first 5G distribution ratio and the first 5G market share in the country.\nChina Mobile Zhejiang and Huawei jointly developed mature practices in scenic spots, stadiums, high-speed railways, and CBDs, helping China Mobile Zhejiang to achieve the three-leading network, experience, and market."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does China Mobile Zhejiang improve network quality? How to build the first 5G city?",
        "answer": "Experience optimization solutions and practices for China Mobile Zhejiang in four key scenarios: scenic spots, Asian Games venues, high-speed rail, and CBD.\nThe first scene is: boutique scenic spot. For example, the West Lake is the most popular scenic spot in Hangzhou. During the peak holiday season, the tourist density increases by more than four times, and the daily reception reaches 300,000 people. The demand for multi-service experience such as video and live broadcast is extremely strong. We use the carrier aggregation technology to aggregate 2.6 GHz and 4.9 GHz into a larger bandwidth, from 100 MHz to 200 MHz. To fully utilize the value of the two bands, we use the 2.6 GHz+4.9 GHz coordinated optimization solution to greatly improve user experience and increase the downlink user-perceived rate by 80% for West Lake tourists. The uplink user-perceived rate increases by 100%.\nThe second scene is: boutique venues. The main hall of the Hangzhou Asian Games can accommodate 80,000 spectators. The 2.6 GHz+4.9 GHz ultra-dense network increases the cell bandwidth from 100 Mbit/s to 260 Mbit/s. Distributed MIMO is used to reduce cell interference and increase the downlink user-perceived data rate by 38% and the uplink user-perceived data rate by 64%. By deploying beamforming antennas, the interference from neighboring cells is reduced by 10 pp. The preceding solution increases the user-perceived downlink rate by 3.4 times and the 5G process by 10 times. At the same time, we have achieved quick vision, quick management, and quick optimization in network assurance. It takes only 5 minutes to detect and close problems.\nThe third scenario is: high-quality high-speed rail. Zhejiang province has a high-speed railway mileage of 1880 km. When the high-speed train runs at a speed of 350 km/h, the rate of users drops to the bottom every 3 seconds due to cell handovers along the road, and 80% of areas are interfered by public network cells along the high-speed railway. China Mobile Zhejiang Branch uses the cell combination technology to reduce inter-cell handovers and keep the network rate at a high speed, increasing the average user rate by 20%. The spatial multiplexing technology enables frequency reuse and doubles the resource capacity. This feature reduces the interference caused by the public network to the high-speed railway dedicated network by 30%. We also have a special optimization solution to improve the coverage and speed of the high-speed rail network. The combined solution improves the downlink and uplink 5G user experience rates by 1.9 times and 1.8 times for high-speed railway users, providing the ultimate experience at a speed of 350 km/h.\nThe fourth scenario is: boutique CBD. According to network insights based on cloud-based data (note: cloud-based data in China and crowd-tested data outside China), 5G network coverage in 20% high-rise buildings in Hangzhou is poor, and the camping ratio of 5G users is 10 pp lower than the average. China Mobile Zhejiang deployed 700 Mbit/s in areas with poor 5G coverage and no 5G coverage, increasing the coverage rate by 15%. (700 MHz can penetrate two walls, compared with 2.6 GHz can penetrate only one wall.) To implement ACP intelligent optimization in the existing 700 MHz network, perform ACP intelligent optimization. In addition, China Mobile Zhejiang uses beam-level interference check to accurately and efficiently detect 5G interference sources, which improves the accuracy by 10 times compared with traditional cell check methods.\nThe combination of all the preceding solutions increases 5G users by 15% and 5G traffic by 10%."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does China Mobile Zhejiang do a good job in ensuring the Asian Games?",
        "answer": "The biggest difference in the Asian Games support is that we have provided strong technical support for the smooth progress of the Asian Games through the Asian Games support command screen as an important implementation tool. We have completed the construction of the Asian Games public and private network, and have created a number of landmark achievements of the Metacosmic Asian Games and intelligent viewing.\nThe main advantages of the Asian Games support command screen are the ultimate perception, the ultimate space-time, the ultimate interaction, and the ultimate self-intelligence. Full-time, all-domain, and all-weather ultimate awareness of the Asian Games network, and associated display of the network operation situation in time and space, providing us with a dynamic view of the network operation evolution. Our systems support multi-screen agile and efficient collaborative operations, while our networks are highly intelligent to ensure business continuity.\nWe all-round perception of the network three-dimensional view, build a new security protection system based on the computing network brain, and implement computing network security scheduling. In terms of urban operation, we have visualized urban conditions such as passenger flow, transportation, and economy, and demonstrated the communication support capability of urban operation in an all-round way.\nFor the stadium situation, we monitor and schedule the network situation of the Asian Games venues in real time to ensure that \"user access, service bearing, and perception are guaranteed\". In terms of the AGIS situation, we have realized end-to-end network quality visualization at different levels from the competition system, AGIS network, and competition terminal.\nTo sum up, the Asian Games support command screen provides powerful network operation and security assurance for the Asian Games in a comprehensive, efficient, and real-time manner through the system with the advantages of ultimate perception, ultimate space-time, ultimate interaction, and ultimate self-intelligence."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Introduce the  overview of the  case in Argentina telecom.",
        "answer": "As the largest integrated operator in Argentina, Telecom Argentina has a large number of users in the mobile, broadband, and fixed-line fields. As of 2023, the company has 20.5 million subscribers in mobile, 4.1 million in broadband and 3 million in fixed-line. In recent years, TA's business strategy has shifted from providing independent services to providing convergent services and laying out new digital services in advance.\nHuawei has been cooperating with TA for many years and has achieved excellent business achievements in mobile user experience improvement, fixed network user experience improvement, and convergent charging. NPS has increased by 10%, ranking No. 1. NPS has stimulated user traffic and increased DOU by 12.3%. This further helped TA achieve a 9% increase in mobile subscribers. TA is dedicated to providing users with the best voice and video experience and has built the best experience ranking (ranked No. 1 for six consecutive years)."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does  Telecom Argentina  improve user experience?\nHow to build a Best network?",
        "answer": "Telecom Argentina cooperated with Huawei to develop a series of experience improvement projects, such as high-quality voice, high-quality video, and best-experience ranking.\n1.  Best voice experience: The VOLTE MOS score is 3.8 in the uplink and 3.9 in the downlink. To improve user experience in voice services, the multi-dimensional voice modeling and optimization method is used to achieve basic coverage, reduce interference, and preferentially guarantee high-traffic areas. The grid-level multi-factor optimization model is used to find the global optimal performance parameters, such as the power, azimuth, and downtilt. The MOS in the uplink and downlink reaches 4.23.\n2. Best video experience: SmartCare can view the overall experience insight. Telecom Argentina monitors CEI, QOE, and KQIs every day. Telecom Argentina improves network capacity through 700 MHz+1900 MHz dual-band coordination and network reconstruction from 2T to 4T, solves the network resource congestion problem in the area, and reduces the flow user dissatisfaction rate to 8.27%.\n3. Best experience ranking: According to Huawei's virtual drive test network insight method, Telecom Argentina finds that only 87.2% of the downlink throughput is greater than 5.5 Mbit/s. Similarly, only 75.5% of the uplink throughput is greater than 1 Mbit/s. Telecom Argentina deploys new sites in areas with coverage holes and performs RF optimization in overlapping areas to reduce interference. This greatly improves mobile network experience. The proportion of downlink throughputs greater than 5.5 Mbit/s increases to 93.1%, and the proportion of uplink throughputs greater than 1 Mbit/s increases to 84.6%. According to the OpenSignal third-party network evaluation report, TA ranks No.1 in the downlink experience rate for six consecutive years."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Telecom Argentina develop home broadband services ？",
        "answer": "Currently, the home broadband NPS of TA lags behind the competition. To ensure the experience of FMC high-value users, Telecom Argentina aims to achieve the fixed network NPS No.1 in the next two years.\nTo achieve this goal, Telecom Argentina introduced ADO in 2012 to proactively gain insight into, optimize, and manage home broadband customer experience based on the CEI system. The construction of the CEI system depends on the analysis and modeling of complex indicators in terms of service experience, network connection quality, and home quality. The CEI system can accurately reflect the actual experience of home broadband customers, analyze quality gaps, and track optimization effects. After the system went live in the first half of 23, the ONT and CDN problems have been optimized, and the list of potential low NPS users has been provided. TAs can be retained by compensation packages. To accurately develop FMC subscribers, TAs accurately segment existing subscribers by feature and identify high-ARPU subscribers, home subscribers, and video subscribers. And to these different types of users for precision marketing."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the measures for developing digital services in Telecom Argentina?\nHow to develop digital services?",
        "answer": "In recent years, Telecom Argentina's business strategy has shifted from providing independent services to providing convergent services and laying out new digital services in advance. To achieve this goal, we have been cooperating with Telecom Argentina for many years to gradually integrate a large number of isolated charging systems on the live network to build a fully integrated charging system and better monetize various services. We focus on two initiatives and results:\n1. The first is about developing new customers. Based on the convergent charging system, the Telecom Argentina can launch new products such as cross-marketing within 1-2 days. This speed is important for the Telecom Argentina to quickly occupy the market. During the 2022 World Cup, Telecom Argentina quickly launched a cross-marketing campaign that included pay TV, mobile and internet services using the strengths of its Flow brand in video content. The move has greatly increased the monthly additions of all brands. New users for IPTV \"Flow Flex\" grew sixfold in the month, and new users for mobile \"Flow Pass\" grew 69%. Converged products bring a win-win situation to both the Personal and Flow brands.\n2. The second aspect is about NPS improvement. After a user accesses the network, the Telecom Argentina provides a series of one-stop experience. (Unified customer service center, unified package subscription, unified app, and unified bill), which greatly improves user experience. According to the churn rate data of mobile users in recent years, each cross-marketing promotion can significantly reduce the churn rate of users in the next few months."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please general introduction to the Ethiopian Telecom case.",
        "answer": "Ethiopia Telecom has a history of 129 years. Ethiopia Posts and Telecommunications Bureau was founded in 1894. Currently, Ethiopia Posts and Telecommunications Bureau continues to undergo digital transformation, including micro-finance service release, micro-modular DC modernization, cloud service development, and Mobile Money SuperAPP release.\nOnly 35 million people in Ethiopia have access to banking services, but 72 million have mobile phones. Thus, a series of local initiatives and programmes have been customized, such as mobile inclusive financial services for people without bank accounts; Provide services such as advanced financial services for people with bank accounts.\nUp to now, Ethiopia Telecom has achieved remarkable results: User growth: 34 million registered users in two years, the fastest speed in the industry; Transaction growth: In the past half year, the transaction processing amount is US$12 billion, equivalent to 10% of Ethiopia's GDP. Micro-finance innovation: Huawei has developed 1 million users in the past seven months, surpassing the 400,000 users in the Ethiopian banking industry in the past 20 years."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is the overall development strategy of Ethiopia Telecom 2025?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia Telecom's Lead Growth 2025 strategy aims to lead the industry digitalization process and realize the digitalization of Ethiopia. The core of this strategy is the continuous growth of services. Up to now, Ethiopia Telecom has 72 million mobile and fixed network users and achieved a penetration rate of 47% of Mobile Money services, that is, 34.8 million users. By expanding the service boundary, Ethiopia Telecom has achieved a compound growth rate of more than 20% in the past three years.\nEthiopia Telecom has been striving to achieve ultimate user experience and excellent service operations through digital transformation, which is closely related to Ethiopia Telecom's strategy of becoming a leader in digital solutions."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "\nWhat are the achievements of Ethiopia Telecom's the cornerstone of inclusive finance and digitalization?",
        "answer": "Telebirr is the cornerstone of inclusive finance and digitalization in Ethiopia and has achieved remarkable results in three areas.\n1. User development: The number of telecom subscribers was converted into the number of telebirr subscribers. The number of telecom subscribers was over 47% in two years. The main ways of transformation are agent network and online marketing; The number of registered users is 34 million in two years, the fastest in the industry.\n2. Transaction growth: Connected to 20+ banks, 40+ public service organizations, and 60K+ merchants, enabling users to access common services, such as bank transfer, car refueling, digital lottery, tax payment, and e-commerce. Over the past six months, US$12 billion was handled, equivalent to 10% of GDP.\n3. Microfinance innovation: Based on local market requirements, Huawei designed and launched 5+ micro-finance services, and controlled the bad debt rate to less than 2% through end-to-end risk control. Market Insight found that 25 million people borrowed over the past year, but only 400,000 borrowed and were mortgaged. Mortgage requires property mortgage, and is not real-time, and user experience is poor. Mainstream people spend between 100-10K birr a month, and people often need these funds to weather temporary crises because of their unstable incomes. Therefore, micro-financial product design: based on user credit, real-time cash loans to meet users' emergency needs. Repayment cycle, which is based on the payroll cycle, i.e. weekly and monthly; The loan amount is limited to the user's requirements. Interest rates refer to local competitive prices, but thousands of people and thousands of faces, because everyone's credit is different. 1 million subscribers in the last seven months, surpassing the 400,000 subscribers the banking industry has grown over the past 20 years."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How did Ethiopia Telecom develop and implement mobile financial services?",
        "answer": "To make full use of the value of huge telecom users, Ethiopia Telecom uses the unified experience of all-channel users to accelerate the transformation of telecom users to Mobile Money users. For example, the packages displayed on the mobile money app and the telecom app are the same. In this case, the 10% reward provided by Ethiopian Telecom through the mobile money channel can convert telecom users more quickly.\nAt the same time, Ethiopia Telecom uses the new BSS platform to provide the Flexi point package, which converts any resource to the point consumption and DIY customized package. In this way, Ethiopia Telecom provides personalized offerings for all users based on events and festivals. Flexible release of marketing promotions such as groups.\nFinally, the real-time orchestration service dashboard is used to form a closed loop, maximizing user value. The new service operation platform improves O&M efficiency by four times and ensures that the system downtime is less than 1 hour per year."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Ethiopia Telecom achieve  high-quality user-centric operations through the digital transformation of O&M?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia Telecom builds a digital operation platform to implement data-driven precise decision-making and build high-quality user-centric operations. In this way, Ethiopia Telecom:\n1. Precise Mobile Money development: Through the convergence of commercial and network data, the mobile money service (including channel agents and users) is developed accurately and efficiently. The number of users reaches 34+ million in two years, the promotion conversion rate of target users is improved by three times, and the revenue increases .\n2. Efficient customer complaint handling: Collects and analyzes network, terminal, and service experience data in quasi-real time to quickly locate the root cause of complaints, and helps the customer complaint handling personnel efficiently reply and close the closed-loop.\n3.Proactive VIP experience management: Real-time service quality monitoring is provided for VIP users, implementing proactive experience management and improving the satisfaction of key customers."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Ethiopia Telecom support the digital transformation and development of operations?\n",
        "answer": "To achieve data-driven efficient operation, Ethiopia Telecom continuously enriches its digital operation platform capabilities through the following three aspects:\n1. Converged platform evolution: Continuously build solid data foundation (O+B+S converged data governance) and intelligent engine (policy+AI+knowledge computing) to support various application scenarios.\n2. Collaboration between business and network: For business operation scenarios, precise data analysis is used to achieve collaborative development between business and network. These application scenarios include precise user segmentation, product design, channel development, and precision marketing.\n3. Perception system establishment: A three-dimensional integrated perception evaluation system is systematically established to bridge networks and business scenarios from network performance, service quality, and customer experience, implementing intelligent perception, automatic analysis, and closed-loop decision-making."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Kenya Safaricom Overview & Business Achievements",
        "answer": "As a leading telecom carrier in Africa, Safaricom is the first one to realize a full-stack digital transformation over the past 15 years, including digital services, digital operation and digital infrastructure. Through digital transformation, Safaricom has achieved 66% of the MBB market share, No.1 for Home Connections, 97% of Mobile Money market share and Best Network NPS."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce the overview of Kenya Safaricom's Digital Intelligence Transformation and Achievements.",
        "answer": "Safaricom is the first one to realize a full-stack digital transformation over the past 15 years, including digital services, digital operation and digital infrastructure. \nSince Safaricom launched the first Mobile Money platform M-PESA in 2007, innovative digital services such as LIPA NA M-PESA, M-PESA GLOBLE, M-PESA SUPPER APP, FULIZA etc. have been implemented through its continuous innovation and evolution. Up to now, Safaricom’s MM has achieved 97% of the market share in Kenya. More than 70% of Kenya's GDP is carried by M-PESA, and MM revenue accounts for nearly half of Safaricom's total revenue. These digital services greatly facilitate Kenyan people's life and enriches Kenyan people's digital life, become one of the most successful cases in the global.\nWith the rapid development of communications technologies and services, Safaricom's network Operation is facing unprecedented challenges, including but not limited to Organizations, Platforms, Criterial, and Processes that need to be upgraded and adapted to the new development. In recent years, Safaricom has put more attention to digital Operation transformation and built its advanced digital platforms based on its E2E business process of \"planning, construction, Operation, optimization, and marketing\". In the past few years, Safaricom has launched NG-NOC, CVM, CRM and other systems, especially in 2023 launched the industry-leading SOC platform which implement data-driven and Fixed-Mobile converged network performance monitoring, user experience management, and CXO business smart decision-making support. Through continuous organization transformation, process reconstruction, new criterial setup and digital operations, Safaricom significantly improved its operational efficiency and achieved business success.\nNetwork, DC, and Cloud are the core infrastructures of Safaricom. In addition to the continuous leadership of Mobile, Home broadband, and Cloud networks, in recent years Safaricom has invested in 3000+ site D.G Hybrid power Reconstruction, 2000+ site Solar green power Modernization, integrate new intelligent energy O&M system, and built a new-generation world-class Limuru Datacenter. Through those efforts, Safaricom has built an advanced “Digital, Green, Efficient, Simplified, and Intelligent” network infrastructure, for example, most of sites are“0” D.G and powered by green energy. These methods support Safaricom to realize the OPEX saving, business development Assurance, and Carbon Emissions Reduction."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce Kenya Safaricom MPESA digital service development.",
        "answer": "Safaricom MPESA has gone through two stages of development in the past 15 years, and as a mature mobile payment service provider, MPESA will also enter its third stage of development. In these three stages, MPESA has experienced from traditional wallet business, to the second stage of financial business, industrialized payment business and refined operations, to the third stage of open ecology. With the continuous development of mobile payment business, MPESA has become an important growth engine for Safaricom. In the first stage, it accounted for 19.2% of Safaricom's overall revenue, and now accounts for 38.3% (MPESA business is already Safaricom's largest single business entity, surpassing data and voice services). Now MPESA is still maintaining double-digit growth every year and is expected to account for 50% of Safaricom's business scale in the future.\nIn order to support the business demands of the three phases of MPESA, Huawei assisted Safaricom in improving its capabilities in three dimensions: business development, technology platform, and operation and maintenance effectiveness, achieving the continuous development of MPESA business."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What businesses have Kenya Safaricom MPESA developed in mobile finance?",
        "answer": "Financial business is MPESA’s main innovative business to increase ARPU value in the second phase.\nMPESA's innovative business started with the small and micro lending business-Fuliza. In the past four years of business development, Fuliza business has developed rapidly and currently has 13M users. However, it is currently encountering bottlenecks in business development, and the number of registered users of Fuliza is sluggish.\nIn order to further grow in the financial business field, MPESA has developed new businesses on the one hand, and on the other hand, it has also continued to explore existing opportunities for lending business. In new business areas, MPESA actively carries out financial business, including money market funds, stocks, insurance, etc. In the existing loan business, users are segmented in a targeted manner, and services such as agency lending, supply chain finance, and micro enterprise loans are provided. For individual users, we have worked intensively to develop a set of user value management processes from user registration, to user activation, to continuous improvement of user value."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Kenya Safariom achieve high-quality user development in business development?",
        "answer": "Background: Safaricom business development is based on the Mobile connectivity. To achieve a high quality of the mobile business growth, Safaricom thinks that the key factors can be summarized as the User Cube business model.\nLayer1: Firstly, it’s the User Foundation targeting on 4G user increasing which they achieved 3M users growth. Secondly, to encourage the user to be Giga User, the user with more than 1GB traffic per month. As the comparison, when user from a non giga user to be a giga user, more than 160% usage growth. At last, Safaricom focuses on the user value to accelerate the postpaid user development bringing more than 130% ARPU growth.\nSo, by User Foundation, User Usage, User Value, the User Cube business development model accelerate the transformation from the user scale-up phase to e value-based digital operation phase.\nLayer2: During the execution, Safaricom built its own profiling system for digital marketing. \nFor example,  the aggregation of SOC and mobile money data helps the full service user profiling. We can easily filter out the target user for 4G user migration with their location, affordability, data usage. \nAfter the growth of user accessed to 4G network, the next cycle is to encourage user usage. By the app behavior profiling, it becomes more direct usage excitation by app bundle.\nThen, more active days is next actions on business development. As currently the prepaid user is still the majority, by the profiling of different product demands of users, we can identify the relevance between a specific product and user group.\nLayer3: All in all, the foundation enabler is the leading user experience."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Safaricom improve the user experience?",
        "answer": ""
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Kenya Safaricom improve customer experience for key To C events?",
        "answer": "Traditional customer experience focuses on passive response and cannot be proactively guaranteed. Kenya Safaricom has added three valuable scenarios in the customer experience domain: \"Key Event Assurance\", \"VIP Proactive Care\", and \"MPESA Experience Assurance\". In addition, Kenya Safaricom identifies, locates, and solves problems from three levels: CXO, department director, and engineer. The AHT was reduced from 235 minutes to less than 30 minutes.\nKey Event Assurance: On September 6, KICC held the Africa Climate Summit 2023. \nCXO: found that the number of subscribers and service volume in the KICC area keep increasing, and alarms indicating poor user experience are generated for some services in the KICC area through the KIA monitoring dashboard. CXO requires SOC department to provide key assurance for the KICC region and handle the experience problems found immediately.\nHOD: understand the KPIs and traffic changes of CS, PS, and VOLTE services every 5 minutes on the KICC assurance dashboard.\nEngineers: obtain top cause values, top terminals, and top cells of VOLTE call drops, demarcate problems based on SOC platform and send trouble tickets to frontline engineers for troubleshooting.\n\nMPESA Experience Assurance：MPESA is the most important services for Safaricom. There are more than 96% of active users are using this service. Safaricom team create a dashboard for monitors KQIs that are closely related to M-PESA service users, usage times, data service traffic, and user experience in real time. When there is a KQI in abnormal, engineer can do multi-dimensional analysis.\n\nVIP Proactive Care: The SOC platform is used to improve VIP user experience from monitoring, analysis, and closed-loop end-to-end process. This section describes how Safaricom uses the SOC platform to monitor, demarcate, analyze, and close-loop VOLTE one-way audio scenarios of VIP users, improving user experience."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Kenya Safaricom to ensure business success through collaborative operations?",
        "answer": "Kenya Safaricom's business success also benefits from its single-domain and cross-domain experience and optimization, experience and O&M, and collaborative operation of experience and services. Build the best network and provide the best experience through value-based precise planning and competition analysis and assurance. Establish an SOC-centric E2E network planning, service development, and service operation mechanism to support the rapid development of core services and digital financial services.\nFirst, experience and optimization collaboration. Take WhatsApp experience assurance as an example. We provide E2E service and experience monitoring and insight, multi-dimensional data association and analysis, and quickly identify problem cells and root causes. Based on the network optimization service, all-dimensional basic optimization, core network and RAN optimization, and WhatsApp optimization are performed. In addition, the optimization results are visible online, greatly improving user satisfaction and reducing customer complaints by more than 15%.\nSecond, collaboration between experience and optimization. Based on the capabilities of SOC FBB and SOC MBB, we have streamlined the work order system, charging system, and CVM system to implement automatic work order dispatch, greatly improving FO work efficiency. In addition, the system can analyze affected services and affected users in real time. Based on the service impact level, the system can send care SMS messages in real time, reward care packages in real time, and send fault rectification notifications to implement No Need to Call, improving user experience and satisfaction.\nThird, experience and service collaboration. Fintech services and GSM services can promote each other. GSM service data can also coordinate 360-degree service insights and user development of financial services. Take the OverDraft service as an example. Based on the multi-digit correlation analysis of SOC platform experience data and OverDraft platform data, 2.8 million high-value users are accurately identified, which brings great significance to the development of OverDraft services."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is Kenya Safaricom's green strategy?",
        "answer": "Kenya Safaricom is the largest integrated carrier in Kenya. It is responsible for providing stable network connections for more than 30+ million users across the country. In the past three years, Kenya's oil price has increased by 55%, and electricity fees have doubled. More importantly, to provide Kenyan people with higher-speed network experience, networks have accelerated to 4/5G. With Safaricom's 5G deployment, (In 25 years, the number of users will increase from 200,000 to 3+ million.) As a result, the power consumption of the site increases by 1.9 times, the energy expenditure of the entire network increases significantly, and the carbon emission increases significantly. The overall power supply in Kenya is unstable. The power supply varies greatly in different regions.  As a result, the availability of many sites is greatly affected, which brings great challenges to our network supply.\n\nKenya Safaricom has always been a socially responsible company. We have a clear ESG strategy (2040) and our goal is to achieve carbon emission NetZero by 2040. For site integration facilities, we value site availability PAV, as well as energy expenditure and carbon emissions per bit. One represents the stability of our infrastructure and whether it can bring stable and reliable network experience to consumers. The other represents the energy consumption and carbon emission level of our infrastructure, bringing cheaper and high-quality networks and greener social development."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are Kenya Safaricom's specific green development actions/measures?",
        "answer": "1. We carefully analyzed the energy infrastructure structure and energy consumption pain points of the entire network. The most important thing is to fundamentally change the energy supply structure of our site infrastructure, focusing on \"oil and light advance\". X years ago, Safaricom's XXX site required diesel generators to work for more than X hours every day to supply power, resulting in energy consumption, O&M, and carbon emissions. Therefore, Safaricom and Huawei jointly introduced a diesel hybrid system, which uses the energy storage and circulation capabilities of lithium batteries. The D.G. running time is greatly reduced by XX%.\n2. In addition, we clearly realize that PV is the first choice for clean energy in the future. Therefore, we are actively introducing PV systems. Currently, XX% of sites have deployed PV systems to further reduce the proportion of fossil energy supply.\n3. Finally, after changing the energy supply structure, we and Huawei are still trying to introduce intelligent technologies. By analyzing parameters such as equipment operating power consumption, mains supply status, and PV power generation efficiency, we introduce artificial intelligence technologies to dynamically adjust the energy storage cycle efficiency in real time, significantly improving energy supply efficiency. The site PAV is further improved and the power consumption is reduced by 1X%.\nA set of indicator systems is required to guide site selection and solution design. Network Carbon Emission Intensity (NCI) is a very important indicator, which measures the carbon dioxide emitted per unit flow. A smaller value indicates a higher carbon emission level. This indicator also indicates the energy consumption level and OPEX level of the network. In Kenya Safaricom, we recommend this KPI as a network appraisal KPI and continuously optimize it. From 720 in 2019 to 330 in 2021, the target is to 65 in the future."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is the outlook for the future of Kenya Safaricom site infrastructure?",
        "answer": "Faced with the challenges of increasing energy consumption and unstable energy prices in the future, as well as Safaricom NetZero's strategy and determination, we will firmly accelerate the introduction of clean energy and intelligent technologies. In the future, we aim to supply XX% of our energy from clean energy. The entire site infrastructure is dynamically adjusted in minutes to seconds using AI. Become a real intelligent green site network in the future."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How to build Kenya Safaricom's data center architecture strategy in the Kenya SFC case?",
        "answer": "Kenya Safaricom is the largest integrated operator in Kenya with more than 30million subscribers. With Safaricom's 5G deployment (number of users will increase from 0.2 million to 3+ million by 2025), To H home broadband service development (300,000 households to 1+ million by 2025), Continuous growth of MPESA services (Cloud-based architecture, increasing the number of transactions processed per second from 3000 to 5000 by 2025), and DC Colo's business development (1000+ racks can be leased in colo cabinets by 2025). Data volume and computing power are increasing rapidly. To match and support network evolution and service revenue growth, Safaricom proposes the \"1+4+X\" next-generation green DC target network architecture as the infrastructure foundation of services. The new DC architecture is gradually implemented through DC construction, reconstruction of old DCs, service migration, and closure of some equipment rooms.\nThe future-oriented \"1+4+X\" data center architecture will be built around the Limuru DC as the central DC. For the Central DC, the number of cabinets is greater than 600, the bandwidth is 400 Gbit/s, and the latency is less than 50 ms. For the Region DC, the number of cabinets ranges from 200 to 400, the bandwidth is 100 Gbit/s, and the latency is less than 30 ms. For the Edge DC, the number of cabinets is less than 50, the bandwidth is 50 Gbit/s, and the latency is less than 10 ms. Safaricom's next-generation green data center network has four features: Green (using advanced solutions and technologies, PUE < 1.4), Reliability (Tier III+ design for simultaneous maintenance); Smart (The intelligent O&M technology is used to achieve 7 x 24 x 365 O&M, and platform tools are used to replace manual operations), Safety (diversity design, meeting level 7 security requirements)."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce the history/process of AIS Thailand digital transformation.",
        "answer": "Focusing on AIS Thailand's comprehensive digital strategy “Cognitive Tech-Co”, let's look at the digital transformation journey and practices in the experience domain:\nAIS comprehensively promoted digital transformation through four key steps:\n1. Define transformation strategy and maturity assessment: The maturity assessment is conducted based on the TMForum’s CEM maturity model to identify key gaps.\n2. Select high-value scenarios and build digital platform: Identify high-value scenarios (customer service, network operation, and market support) in the 2C domain by breaking down the transformation strategy, and identify high-value scenarios (complaint handling, VIP assurance, and data monetization). Build a unified digital platform as the foundation to support various business scenarios.\n3. Organization and process optimization: Identify business pain points, streamline cross-department processes and data breakpoints, establish a customer-centric NSOC team, and work closely with surrounding business departments.\n4. Continuous practice and evolution: Aligning with the targets of business departments, implementing in three domains: \"operational efficiency improvement, customer experience improvement, revenue growth\", continuously practice and evolution."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the major aspects of digital transformation of AIS Thailand experience?",
        "answer": "for these three areas, let's look at the top half of the screen, with AIS best practices:\n1. Operation efficiency improvement: Take the value scenario of \"complaint handling\" as an example. By opening the complaint process, identifying target gaps and process pain points, introducing UC such as CCA/CCH on the SmartCare digital platform, and deeply integrating with the customer's installed base IM/SSM, the call agent AHT reduced by 25% and FCR increased by 15 PCT within one year.\n2. Customer experience improvement: Traditional customer experience mainly focuses on passive response, and cannot be proactively guaranteed. The churn analysis is based on the BSS system, without network cause analysis. Based on the O+B+S converged data, AIS adds two value scenarios: VIP active care and experience-driven churn analysis. The churn rate decreases by 18% (including prepaid and postpaid) and VIP subscriber complaint rate decreases by 14% within three years.\n3. Data monetization: Traditional marketing is based on BSS domain data and experience-based/diffuse marketing, with low conversion rate. By leveraging O+B+S converged data and Customer 360 intelligent profile, with AI technology, marketing success rate is improved by accurately matching people, place, and offer. The AIS also spills data and capabilities to partners (such as BTS/VGi), releasing the value of converged data and increasing business revenue by $6.6 million within one year."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce the digital transformation of AIS Thailand O&M.",
        "answer": "Since 2018, AIS Thailand has cooperated with Huawei to implement digital O&M transformation.\nAIS digital O&M transformation is divided into three phases.\n1,Automatic Operations. Since 2018, AIS has cooperated with Huawei to transform from manual O&M to automatic O&M. By using the Auto Correlation, Auto RCA, and Auto Diagnosis functions for the network alarms, the original 4M/Month alarms are reduced to 0.1M TT/Job. Helping increase FO efficiency by 25%.\n2,Service-oriented Operations. In the second phase, network faults are reduced after automation, but the impact on services not getting any better. Therefore, AIS uses the NOC and SOC synergy to transform alarm-oriented O&M into service-oriented O&M. It identifies service impacts when network faults occur and prioritizes faults that have great service impacts. This greatly reduces revenue loss and further improved FO efficiency by 10%.\n3,Zero Touch Operations. For the future, AIS is cooperating with Huawei to transform automatic O&M into intelligent O&M. AI is used to analyze alarms and predict risks, so as to achieve the goal of E2E fault automation > 95%."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the major aspects of AIS Thailand O&M digital transformation?",
        "answer": "The Intelligent O&M Transformation Journey of AIS comes from the transformation of the platform, process, and organizational talent.\n1,Platform Evolution. Transform the traditional Silo system into the Unified Platform. Introduce Huawei SmartCare and AUTIN to the Unified Platform and integrate these two systems. In addition, introduce iStudio@AUTIN to support talent transformation.\n2,Process Optimization. Automatic Root Cause Identification and Service Impact Analysis are implemented by using AUTIN Robot for complex E2E troubleshooting. Automatic closure of faults that can be recovery remotely is completed in AUTIN Robot. For faults that need to be recovery onsite, an Job is automatically dispatched to the field engineer.\n3,Organization & Talent Transformation. Integrate the skills of FOs. Combine the original three wireless teams into one team and combine the original four core/bearer network teams into one team. Merge the NOC and SOC teams into the NSOC team to support NE Problem Demarcation in the Complain Handling process and Service Impact Analysis in the Incident Handling process.\nTransform traditional O&M engineers into self-orchestration DevOps engineers. Through the transformation of platforms, processes, and organizational talent, AIS is evolving “Towards Zero Touch Operations” digital O&M transformation."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does AIS Thailand achieve 5G leadership?",
        "answer": " AIS Thailand integrates O+B+S data, enables precision investment based on BI, enables potential customer acquisition based on AI, and enables precision marketing based on DI, achieving a leading 5G market.\n1. BI enables precise investment: Through Device & Network &Tariff collaboration, evaluates and scores areas (where there is 5G device & tariff but no 5G network), identifies high-value areas, and builds 5G sites. The ROI of each site is increased by 120% (compared with 4G).\n2. AI-enabled potential customer acquisition: A user-centric 5G data set is constructed based on OSS+BSS converged data, and the AI potential customer model is used to accurately identify high-potential 5G users. The number of AIS 5G subscribes increases from 1 million to over 4 million within two years.\n3. DI enables precision marketing: The Smart Decision solution introduces digital twins technologies based on insights into people, place, product and experience, provides precise package suggestions for target user groups, and supports efficient decision-making. The 5G ARPU is improved by 10% to 15% (compared with 4G).\nExcellent network performance is the basis for leading the 5G market. After the 5G network is established, AIS has introduced advanced technologies to continuously optimize network performance, achieving leading performance and experience. Among them, the 5G population coverage ratio reaches 99%, the 5G camping ratio reaches 82%, and the 5G downlink speed reaches 1.1 Gbps, ranking No. 1 in Thailand. Conversely, leading network experience can better support 5G user development and marketing."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the benefits of AIS Thailand data convergence?",
        "answer": "AIS Thailand officially launched its home broadband plan in 2015 and began to develop home broadband users on a large scale in 2018. In less than five years, the number of home broadband users of AIS Thailand has grown to more than 2 million. The broadband revenue has increased by 20% every year. While the market share and revenue have increased rapidly, the home broadband user experience has become the first in Thailand. The success of AIS Thailand broadband service development depends on customers' digital capability construction and application. As early as 20 years ago, ADO premium home broadband solution has been used as a digital operation platform for AIS Thailand HBB service experience management and UPSELL. \n1.Cockpit is mainly applied to AIS’s FBB departments. It proactively identifies problems about home broadband user experience and service quality, implements proactive and continuous optimization at multiple layers of business, networks, and services, ensuring the experience and satisfaction of existing users and reducing churn.\n2.UPSELL is mainly used by the customer's CRM department. ADO provides household-level user profiles based on insights of household value, online behavior, application preference, and experience. This greatly expands the market space for AIS, increases the single-user ARPU and increases revenue with high quality.\n3.Finally, in the O&M field, ADO provides quality insight from three dimensions: connection, network, and service experience. In addition to E2E analysis at each layer, root cause analysis can be performed across layers. This is effective for solving complex customer experience and quality problems, greatly reducing ineffective site visits. "
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does AIS Thailand develop charging services?\n",
        "answer": "AIS is Thailand's largest operator with about 50 million subscribers. As you can see it provides a wide range of services for individuals, families, and enterprises. Our cooperation with AIS Thailand started in 2017, we provided OCS to support the monetization of services. The name of the project is avatar. Since then, we have made a series of achievements. For example, in 2020, AIS Thailand launched the first 5G SA charging system. This year, AIS Thailand is delivering the first cloud-native charging system based on the N-LIVE solution.\nThe key capabilities that we call CFO for short: Cloud-native, Fast TTM, All-in-one.\nFirst, OCS uses a series of latest cloud native technologies, such as gray release, N-LIVE, and full-stack heterogeneous, to build a reliable, agile, and cost-effective platform for AIS Thailand.\nThe second key capability we provide for AIS is fast time to market, here we have 2 cases: Quick offer configuration and DIY offer.\nThe third key capability we provide for AIS Thailand is convergence. AIS Thailand launched the first 5G SA charging system overseas, and the first system with full cloud native architecture with N-LIVE solution. "
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does the AIS Thailand develop the video RBT service?",
        "answer": "Based on our 41 million mobile subscribers and high VOLTE penetration rate, AIS Thailand launchs Video RBT service which upgrades call waiting from audio to video to develop new digital services；\n \tVideo RBT improves user experience, To C users can watch short videos for entertainment and DIY video RBTs for social sharing. In addition, To B advertising revenue is generated by playing tourism video and enterprise advertisements for users；\n \tAIS Thailand develops services in three-step. First, users are allowed to experience new services through free trial. We promote terminal OEMs such as Samsung and Huawei to upgrade more terminal. And then we obtain the list of subscribers available on the device through SmartCare and enabled for free trial. Then, high-quality content is introduced to activate subscribers through personalized content operation. Currently, more than 4000 video content of multiple CPs has been aggregated. Finally, monetize content and advertisements to obtain new revenue."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is Jazz's transformation?",
        "answer": "As one of the major carriers in Central Asia, Jazz actively embraces digitalization. Mr. Aamir Hafeez, CEO of Jazz, said: we are going to transform Jazz into a digital lifestyle player because our ambition is much bigger and broader.\nPhase 1: O&M efficiency improvement. Jazz's digital transformation greatly improves operation capabilities and O&M efficiency through CCA/CCH and VIP user assurance.\nPhase 2: The best experience is provided to customers through VOLTE and JazzFi and the continuous growth of users.\nPhase 3: Digital life enablement, which is extended to the experience improvement of multiple Jazz apps, enables users' digital life, and improves the marketing success rate by supporting marketing based on user behavior data.\nPhase 4: Build a digital ecosystem, introduce more digital products to provide users with seamless digital life experience, and achieve Deliver valuable digital experiences for customers 1440 minutes of a day.\nJazz's ARPU increased by 20% and DOU increased by 3.5 times through the four-phase digital transformation. "
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the problems with the Jazz user experience? How to improve user experience",
        "answer": "In the early stage of JazzFi development, there are no monitoring methods for user experience. As a result, there are many complaints from customers, fault locating and handling are time-consuming and labor-consuming. In addition, potential users cannot be accurately identified, for example, whether the mobile phone supports VOWi-Fi and whether the switch is turned on.\nPhase 1: O&M efficiency improvement. Jazz's digital transformation greatly improves operation capabilities and O&M efficiency through CCA/CCH and VIP user assurance.\nPhase 2: The best experience is provided to customers through VOLTE and JazzFi and the continuous growth of users.\nPhase 3: Digital life enablement, which is extended to the experience improvement of multiple Jazz apps, enables users' digital life, and improves the marketing success rate by supporting marketing based on user behavior data.\nPhase 4: Build a digital ecosystem, introduce more digital products to provide users with seamless digital life experience, and achieve Deliver valuable digital experiences for customers 1440 minutes of a day."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What are the challenges in Jazz VoLTVOLTE development? How to improve VOLTE customer experience?",
        "answer": "At the initial stage, the number of Jazz VOLTE subscribers increases slowly, and the migration efficiency is low. Jazz has a series of initiatives:\n1,Based on the perception-based indicator system, the system automatically locates problems in real time and ensures end-to-end user experience.\n2,16 groups of precise segmentation, corresponding to 6 marketing solutions, effectively improving the marketing success rate compared with the traditional wide-spread solution.\n3,Geographically displays the distribution of VOLTE subscribers, matches the corresponding marketing scheme, and ranks regions by the number of VOLTE subscribers.\n4,Digitally display the VOLTE user conversion rate and rapidly increase the number of users. By 2022, the number of VOLTE users will increase by 10 million, exceeding the target."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "How does Jazz develop OTT services & Cash through the smartcare? \nHow does Jazz achieve precision marketing?",
        "answer": "SmartCare brings great value to the stable operation of OTT services. The following section is the process of our entire real-time marketing platform.\n1. many network events (such as Internet access, receiving SMS messages, and receiving calls) are generated anytime and anywhere. Using probes, the SmartCare can capture these events in real time. 2. Submit the subscribed real-time event data to the marketing management module through the complex event processing process. 3.The marketing management module automatically matches customer profiles and input events and identifies marketing content to be pushed to users. 4. The push channels are diversified.  the push channels can be through the call center, SMS/App/Web, and offline stores.\nIn general, the features of SmartCare-based real-time context-based marketing are as follows:\nA. Real-time: We can identify customer requirements in the first place.\nB. Precise: The recommended content matches the customer exactly.\nC. Convenient: The app is non-intrusive and can quickly complete marketing settings and distribution.\nD. Flexible: Any combination of geographical location events and user behavior events.\n\nHow to achieve precision marketing:\nCurrently, the SmartCare real-time marketing platform has been used by 13 self-operated apps and has greatly improved our app development. For example:\nThe number of Deikho (original content platform for streaming) users has tripled a year.\nJazhCash users grow rapidly, with a 150-fold increase in the number of users.\nBaJao (a music platform) users increased by 70 times a year.\nThe number of Tamasha (Jazz TV) subscribers increased by 7 times.\nJazz (app) users grow fourfold in a year."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "What is the overview of MTN?",
        "answer": "As the largest mobile telecom operator in Africa, MTN provides voice, data, and financial technology services to more than 290 million customers in 19 markets, and maintains good business performance. In the first half of 2023, MTN continued its growth as exhibited by key operating indicators of  revenue growth, subscribers increase, and EBITDA margin.  MTN has also achieved  “the most valuable African brand” title."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce MTN's Digital Transformation Strategy - PACE ",
        "answer": "In 2021 MTN released Ambition 2025 strategy to accelerate growth and unlock the value of its infrastructure assets and platforms. To expedite the execution of Ambition 2025 strategy, a new framework is launched. This framework breaks down the strategy at the network level and proposes the strategic concept “PACE”, focusing on four aspects:\n1. Platform, ecosystem, and service (P): Leverage platforms and related digital ecosystems to achieve revenue growth.\n2. Agile operation model (A): Improve the agility of working methods, governance, and organizational culture.\n3. Connectivity and infrastructure optimization (C): Realize first-class ubiquitous connectivity and infrastructure monetization based on converged networks.\n4. Ultimate experience (E): Provides ultimate user experience through connections, platforms, and ecosystems.\nThrough PACE, MTN adheres to the general concept of digital transformation and further breaks down the PACE into 15 pillars and these pillars are further broken down into 45 specific programs hence providing a top-down mapping and guidance of achieving the Ambition 2025 objectives through a PACE framework using specific programs. \nDigital Infrastructure and Digital O&M will aim at Leading Performance, Digital Experience will aim at Leading Experience, Digital Services and To C/To H Services Enablement will aim at Leading Business, and Talent Transformation will serve as a solid foundation for all programs."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Please introduce MTN's digital transformation history and practices.",
        "answer": "On the road of digital transformation exploration, MTN and Huawei have deeply cooperated with each other and achieved phased milestones. Phase 1 from 2017 to 2019, focused on the deployment of digital platforms, and phase 2 from 2020 to 2022, focused on the improvement of digital O&M efficiency. Use AUTIN to implement Auto TT & Work Order and Auto Diagnose UC, and enable SOC operation and customer care assistant based on SmartCare. In the third phase, from 2023 onwards, MTN will focus on user experience and continuously improve the scores of Facebook, Umlaut, and N-NPS to build a second to none experience and maintain the top ranking.\nIn the future, MTN will shift its focus from efficiency improvement to experience improvement to enable business success and provide better services for more customers."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Why does MTN achieve leading experience?",
        "answer": "To achieve the second to none, experience, MTN adopts the NPS leading position as the experience measurement standard and incorporates the NPS KPIs to benchmark between its 19 OPCOs.\nThrough Digital Operation transformation N-NPS, Umlaut crowd test, and Umlaut DT benchmarking is done and improved with the assistance of the digital platform, MTN uses cross-domain data convergence and analysis to enables the collaboration of NOC and Optimization to achieve excellent network performance and enable the collaboration of Optimization and SOC to achieve good service experience."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "Does the MTN subnet have good experience and practices?",
        "answer": "MTN has been implementing innovative practices in some of its OpCos and has achieved phased achievements. In Ghana, MTN is facing increasing pressure from its competitors in terms of NPS score. The gap between the competitors and MTN's N-NPS score is narrowing. As a result, MTN's leading market position is challenged. By effectively correlating the innovative customer experience index (CEI) with NPS, MTN can quickly identify NPS problems in terms of capacity, experience, and complaints. MIMO site reconstruction is used to solve capacity problems on the RAN side, build solid network infrastructure, and quickly resolve experience-related complaints through NOC-SOC collaboration. Through SOC-Optimization collaboration, the solution effectively resolves user experience problems, continuously improves the NPS score, gradually expands the gap with competitors, maintains the leading position, and greatly increases the traffic volume and user throughput, enabling business success.\nIn Nigeria, MTN focuses on the Facebook experience, but the Facebook user experience lags behind competitors. In addition, MTN has a large-scale and complex network, and it is difficult to improve user experience. To meet the challenges, MTN proposes the concept of model city. MTN makes full use of network data and uses digital methods such as scenario-based parameter optimization and multi-band optimization, intelligent alarm compression, and real-time task tracing to digitalize the entire process from Optimization to O&M, making Abuja the first model city. After several months of continuous efforts, we not only surpassed our competitors in the Facebook experience, but also achieved No.1 for both the Facebook experience and the NPS experience."
    },
    {
        "﻿question": "",
        "answer": ""
    }
]